Guide to the Steven H. Scheuer Collection of Television Program Scripts
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- SPECIALS
  - ENTERTAINMENT SPECIALS
    - The Lucky Strike Special Hal Kanter, undated (Box 435, Folder 6)
    - Marineland Carnival (no author indicated) Producer: Charles Andrews Director: Bob Lehman, 1962 Apr 22 (Box 435, Folder 7)
    - Music for a Christmas Night (no author indicated), 1960 Dec 25 (Box 435, Folder 8)
    - Music USA Cy Howard Producer: Eva Wolas Director: Norman Abbott, 1958 Sep 8 (Box 435, Folder 9)
    - Nightclubs, New York George Foster Jay Burton Producers-Directors: Abe Burrows, Perry Lafferty, 1960 Apr 7 (Box 435, Folder 10)
    - Paris a la Mode (no author indicated), undated (Box 435, Folder 11)
    - Phil Silvers on Broadway Will Glickman Joseph Stein Allan Sherman Producer: Allan Sherman Director: Bill Hobin, 1958 May 13 (Box 436, Folder 1)
    - Phil Silvers Special (no author indicated), undated (Box 436, Folder 2)
    - Pontiac Four-in-One-Show with Alfred E. Neuman and the Mad Revue (no author indicated), undated (Box 436, Folder 3)
    - The Rock 'n Roll Revue (no author indicated) Producer: Frederic Heider Director: Cort Steen, 1957 May 4 (Box 436, Folder 4)
    - Rodgers and Hammerstein (no author indicated), 1954 May 28 (Box 436, Folder 5)
    - Satins and Spurs (no author indicated), undated (Box 436, Folder 6)
    - Something Special (2 copies) Reginald Rose Producer: Michael Abbott Director: Dick Schneider, 1960 Dec 4 (Box 436, Folder 7)
    - Standard Oil 75th Anniversary Show (no author indicated), 1957 Oct 13 (Box 436, Folder 8)
    - Thrills of the Ringling Brothers Barnum and Bailey Circus Frank Wayne Producer: Lawrence White Director: Al Rafkin, 1960 May 27 (Box 436, Folder 9)
    - The Wonderful World of Jack Paar Paul Keyes Bob Howard Producer: Jack Paar Director: Fred Garrison, undated (Box 436, Folder 10)
    - (no title) Peter Ustinov Leslie Stevens, undated (Box 436, Folder 11)
  - DRAMA SPECIALS
    - The Aldrich Family--The Blind Date (no author indicated), 1954 (Box 437, Folder 1)
    - Antigone Sophocles, undated (Box 437, Folder 2)
    - The Ballad of Yermo Red Marcel Klauber William T. Grady, 1956 Jul 30 (Box 437, Folder 3)
    - The Battler A.E. Hotchner Sidney Carroll (Ernest Hemingway), undated (Box 437, Folder 4)
    - Bend to the Wind George Lowther Producer: S. Mark Smith Director: Jack Smight, 1956 May 4 (Box 437, Folder 5)
    - Brand from the Burning Doris Holman, 1955 (Box 437, Folder 6)
    - A Candle in the Sun Tad Mosel, 1953 Oct 28 (Box 437, Folder 7)
    - The Case of the Crimson Kiss Walter Doniger Milton Geiger (Erle Stanley Gardner), undated (Box 437, Folder 8)
    - Crime in the Streets (no author indicated), undated (Box 437, Folder 9)
    - Cynara (no author indicated), undated (Box 437, Folder 10)
    - A Day of Awe (2 copies) Will Lorin Producer: Wiley Hance Director: Jack Sameth, undated (Box 438, Folder 1)
    - Diagnosis: Death (no author indicated), 1958 Jan 17 (Box 438, Folder 2)
    - The Everlasting Road Stefan Zweig Producer: Wiley Hance Director: William R. Ayers, undated (Box 438, Folder 3)
    - The Dispossessed Saul Levitt, undated (Box 438, Folder 4)
    - Feathertop Maurice Valency (Nathaniel Hawthorne), 1955 Oct 24 (Box 438, Folder 5)
    - The Fifth Wheel Whitfield Cook, undated (Box 438, Folder 6)
    - The Final Ingredient Reginald Rose, 1959 Apr 19 (Box 438, Folder 7)
    - Finkle's Comet Herman Raucher, undated (Box 438, Folder 8)
    - Foundations George Bellak Producer: S. Mark Smith, 1956 May 25 (Box 438, Folder 9)
    - Hamlet Shakespeare (with Maurice Evans), undated (Box 438, Folder 10)
    - Harbourmaster Jerry Adelman Carey Wilber, 1957 (Box 438, Folder 11)
    - The Hidden People Jameson Brewer, 1956 (Box 439, Folder 1)
    - High Tor Maxwell Anderson John Monks, 1955 (Box 439, Folder 2)
    - In the French Style Irwin Shaw, undated (Box 439, Folder 3)
    - In the Last Place Stephan Chodorov Producer: Chalmers Dale Director: Bruce Minnix, 1963 Sep 29 (Box 439, Folder 4)
    - The Irritating Angel John McLiam, undated (Box 439, Folder 5)
    - I've Got It Made (no author indicated), undated (Box 439, Folder 6)
    - John Brown's Body Harold Flender Stephen Vincent Benet Producer: R.F. Siemanowski Director: Joseph K. Chomyn, 1962 Jan 14 (Box 439, Folder 7)
    - Johnny Belinda Theodore Apstein, undated (Box 439, Folder 8)
    - Judy and the Brain Sylvia Weld, undated (Box 439, Folder 9)
    - The Laughing Willow Sumner Locke Elliott Producer: Gordon Duff Director: Tom Donovan, 1958 Feb 3 (Box 439, Folder 10)
    - Let It Rain D.J. Powers, 1955 (Box 439, Folder 11)
    - A Letter to Mr. Priest Margaret Cousins, undated (Box 439, Folder 12)
    - The Lights of Chanukah Stephen Longstreet Producer: Wiley Hance Director: William Ayers, undated (Box 439, Folder 13)
    - The Living End George Lefferts Producer: George Lefferts, 1960 (Box 439, Folder 14)
    - The Lord Don't Play Favorites Jo Swerling Hal Stanley, undated (Box 439, Folder 15)
    - The Lost Weekend Will Lorin, undated (Box 440, Folder 1)
    - Ludus Coventriae (Medieval mystery play) (no author), undated (Box 440, Folder 2)
    - Murder Me Gently Sarett Rudley Gore Vidal, 1957 (Box 440, Folder 3)
    - Once Upon a Christmastime (no author indicated), undated (Box 440, Folder 4)
    - Once Upon an Eastertime Reginald Lawrence Producer: William Dozier Director: Martin Manulis, 1954 Apr 18 (Box 440, Folder 5)
    - The Other Place Theodore Apstein Producer: Gordon Duff Director: Jack Smight, 1958 Jan 13 (Box 440, Folder 6)
    - Paper Town Robert J. Shaw Director: John Newland, 1955 Oct 10 (Box 440, Folder 7)
    - Quality Town (no author indicated), undated (Box 440, Folder 8)
    - Ready, Mr. Rosewater? Virginia Mazer, 1957 Apr 14 (Box 440, Folder 9)
    - Return Match (no author indicated), undated (Box 440, Folder 10)
    - Run Like a Thief (no author indicated), undated (Box 440, Folder 11)
    - The Skin of Our Teeth Ellen Violett (Thornton Wilder) Director: Vincent J. Donohue, 1955 Sep 11 (Box 441, Folder 1)
    - A Song for Queen Esther Morton Wishengrad, 1957 Mar 17 (Box 441, Folder 2)
    - The Starmaster Will Schneider Herman Goldberg, undated (Box 441, Folder 3)
    - The Straight and Narrow Hamilton Benz, undated (Box 441, Folder 4)
    - Svengali and the Blonde Alan Handley Charles Gaynor, undated (Box 441, Folder 5)
    - The Trail Blazer James Warner Bellah Russ Hughes Sid Morse, undated (Box 441, Folder 6)
    - Transfusion Michelle Cousin, undated (Box 441, Folder 7)
    - The Trophy Irve Tunick Producer: Wiley Hance Director: Jack Sameth, 1957 Dec 15 (Box 441, Folder 8)
    - Trumpet Man (2 copies) Philo Higley, undated (Box 441, Folder 9)
    - Well, What About You? Dore Sharey, undated (Box 441, Folder 10)
    - Where is Thy Brother? Ernest Kinoy, undated (Box 441, Folder 11)
    - The Yeoman of the Guard William Nichols Gllbert and Sullivan, undated (Box 441, Folder 12)
  - DOCUMENTARY SPECIALS
    - America in Space Martin Caidin, 1961 Dec 1 (Box 442, Folder 1)
    - The America's Cup Races Harry Muheim Producer: Robert L. Bendick, 1962 Sep 17 (Box 442, Folder 2)
    - The Arab World James Benjamin Producer: Charles Romine Director: Roger Englander, 1957 Apr 28 (Box 442, Folder 3)
    - Balance of Terror with Alistaire Cook, James Reston, and others. Douglas Leiterman Producer: Jack Willis Director: Douglas Leiterman, undated (Box 451, Folder 6)
      (Oversize)
    - Ballads from Latin America (no author indicated), 1961 Jun 11 (Box 442, Folder 4)
    - Beyond the Threshold James Benjamin Producer: Robert L. Bendick Director: Jack Sughrue, 1962 Jan (Box 442, Folder 5)
    - Blow-Up at Breezo Point (no author indicated) Producers: Edward M. Jones Director: Allen Robertson Herbert Dorfman, 1963 Jun 21 (Box 442, Folder 6)
    - ... But Never Forget (no author indicated), undated (Box 442, Folder 7)
    - California... the Most (no author indicated), 1963 Mar 14 (Box 442, Folder 8)
    - Castro's Year of Power (no author indicated), undated (Box 442, Folder 9)
    - Chopin Moura Lympany Mel Baily Producer: Mel Baily Director: Arthur Forrest, 1960 (Box 442, Folder 10)
    - Confronted (no author indicated) Producer: George Page, 1963 Dec 2 (Box 442, Folder 11)
    - Conventions 1960 (no author indicated) Producer: Elmer W. Lower Director: Ralph H. Peterson, 1960 Apr 24 (Box 442, Folder 12)
    - Cops and Robbers Philip Reisman, Jr., 1962 Mar 18 (Box 442, Folder 13)
    - Creative America Ernest Kinoy Producer: Pamela Ilott Director: Martin Carr, 1963 Mar 17 (Box 442, Folder 14)
    - Debutante '62 Harry Muheim, undated (Box 442, Folder 15)
    - Destiny's Tot (3 copies) Robert Lindner S. Lee Pogostin Director: Fielder Cook, undated (Box 442, Folder 16)
    - Down the Road Virginia Mazer, undated (Box 442, Folder 17)
    - An Experiment in Excellence Robert Northshield Frank DeFelitta Producers: Robert Northshield Director: Frank DeFelitta, 1963 Sep 19 (Box 443, Folder 1)
    - The Fabulous Fifties (no author indicated), 1960 Jan 19 (Box 443, Folder 2)
    - The First Lady Perry Wolff, undated (Box 443, Folder 3)
    - The Great War Henry Salomon Richard Hanser Producer: Henry Salomon, 1956 Oct 16 (Box 443, Folder 4)
    - Greece: the Golden Age Lou Hazam, 1963 Nov 19 (Box 443, Folder 5)
    - Hollywood Around the World (no author indicated), 1957 (Box 443, Folder 6)
    - Hong Kong Stanley Flink Producer: Stanley Flink, 1961 Feb 2 (Box 443, Folder 7)
    - The House that Jack Built (no author indicated), undated (Box 443, Folder 8)
    - In Common Brotherhood David Davidson, undated (Box 443, Folder 9)
    - The Invisible City (no author indicated), undated (Box 443, Folder 10)
    - Israel: It is No Fable Don Kellerman Producer: Don Kellerman Director: John J. Desmond, 1963 May 8 (Box 443, Folder 11)
    - Junkyard by the Sea (no author indicated), 1960 Dec 19 (Box 443, Folder 12)
    - The Land of Promise Sheldon Stark, undated (Box 443, Folder 13)
    - Light From Lambarene (no author indicated), undated (Box 443, Folder 14)
    - The Long Time Between Edward Gilmore, 1958 Apr 19 (Box 443, Folder 15)
    - Man of the Year (no author indicated), 1953 Dec 6 (Box 443, Folder 16)
    - Mark Twain's America Richard Hanser Producer-Director: Donald B. Hyatt, 1960 (Box 444, Folder 1)
    - Millionaire's Mite Ernest Kinoy, 1960 Mar 3 (Box 444, Folder 2)
    - Minority of One Kristin Eggleston Hunter, 1955 (Box 444, Folder 3)
    - The Negro and the American Promise (no author indicated) Producer: Henry Morganthau III Director: Fred Barzyk, 1963 Jun 24 (Box 444, Folder 4)
    - The Next Revolution Warren Wallace Producer-Director: Warren Wallace, undated (Box 444, Folder 5)
    - George Lefferts Producer: Ben Park, 1955 Oct 9 (Box 444, Folder 6)
    - Now... Nigeria David Shafrin, 1961 (Box 444, Folder 7)
    - Oh, Be Joyful (no author indicated), undated (Box 444, Folder 8)
    - The Other Walls (no author indicated), undated (Box 451, Folder 7)
    - Pablo Picasso--An American Tribute (no author indicated), undated (Box 444, Folder 9)
    - The Peace Corps (no author indicated), 1961 (Box 444, Folder 10)
    - The Peace Corps in Tanganyka (no author indicated), undated (Box 444, Folder 11)
    - Pendleton Roundup (no author indicated), 1957 (Box 444, Folder 12)
    - Portrait of Aly Khan (no author indicated), 1960 (Box 444, Folder 13)
    - A Question of Chairs Lane Slate Producer: Don Kellerman Director: Mel Ferber, 1961 Jan 15 (Box 444, Folder 14)
    - Rebels of the Sierra Maestra (no author indicated), undated (Box 444, Folder 15)
    - Red China--Updated Helen Marmor Producer: Chet Hagan Director: Robert Priaulx, 1959 May 10 (Box 445, Folder 1)
    - The Red Threat (no author indicated), 1962 Mar 26 (Box 445, Folder 2)
    - Remember Us (no author indicated), 1960 Jul 18 (Box 445, Folder 3)
    - The Rise and Fall of Benito Mussolini William W. Kenneally Eldorous L. Dayton Producer: William L. Cooper Walter D. Engels, undated (Box 445, Folder 4)
    - The Roots of Freedom: The Golden Age of Greece Perry Wolff, undated (Box 445, Folder 5)
    - The Sacco-Vanzetti Story Reginald Rose Producer: Alex March Director: Sidney Lumet, 1960 Jun 3 (Box 445, Folder 6)
    - Elliott Baker Producer: Jack Kuney Director: John Desmond, 1959 Dec 6 (Box 445, Folder 7)
    - Seasons of Youth (2 copies) (no author indicated), 1961 Oct (Box 445, Folder 8)
    - The Secret Life of Danny Kaye (no author indicated), 1956 Nov 26 (Box 445, Folder 9)
    - Shakespeare: Soul of an Age Lou Hazam, 1962 (Box 445, Folder 10)
    - Small Explosion Allen Rivkin, 1958 Dec 7 (Box 445, Folder 11)
    - Space--Man's Last Frontier Andrew K. Lewis, 1959 May 24 (Box 445, Folder 12)
    - Stalingrad (no author indicated), undated (Box 446, Folder 1)
    - The Story of St. Patrick Melvin Bailey Producer: Melvin Bailey, 1961 Mar 16 (Box 446, Folder 12)
    - Stranger in the City (no author indicated), 1960 Mar 30 (Box 446, Folder 3)
    - The Subject is Jazz (no author indicated), 1958 Mar 26 (Box 446, Folder 4)
    - Sudan (no author indicated), 1959 Jun 7 (Box 446, Folder 5)
    - Superfluous People (no author indicated), 1962 Jul 26 (Box 446, Folder 6)
    - Ten Seconds that Shook the World Alan Landsburg, 1963 Dec 10 (Box 446, Folder 7)
    - Three, Two, One--Zero Henry Salomon Richard Hanser Producer: Henry Salomon, 1954 Sep 13 (Box 446, Folder 8)
    - A Time for Living (no author indicated), undated (Box 446, Folder 9)
    - To Breathe Free Martin Hoade Producer-Director: Martin Hoade, undated (Box 446, Folder 10)
    - To Win a Crown Bernard Shaw, undated (Box 446, Folder 11)
    - Too Late for Reason (no author indicated), undated (Box 446, Folder 12)
    - Trio Howard Teichmann Richard Lemon Producer: Martin Levin, undated (Box 446, Folder 13)
    - The Twisted Cross Henry Salomon Richard Hanser, 1956 Mar 14 (Box 446, Folder 14)
    - U.S. Grant: An Improbable Hero (no author indicated), undated (Box 446, Folder 15)
    - Vote for What? (no author indicated), 1961 Sep 21 (Box 446, Folder 16)
    - The War That Creeps (no author indicated), undated (Box 446, Folder 17)
    - A Way of Thinking: Secrecy and Survival (no author indicated), undated (Box 447, Folder 1)
    - Whatever Happened to Royalty? Warren Wallace Producer-Director: Warren Wallace, 1963 Sep 9 (Box 447, Folder 2)
    - White House West Wing (no author indicated), 1963 Jul 14 (Box 447, Folder 3)
    - Who Goes There? Robert Abernethy Robert Northshield Producer: Robert Northshield Director: Don McDonough, 1963 Mar 1 (Box 447, Folder 4)
    - The World of Maurice Chevalier Joseph Liss Producer-Director: Eugene S. Jones, 1963 Feb 22 (Box 447, Folder 5)
    - Years of Destiny (no author indicated), 1962 Apr 24 (Box 447, Folder 6)
    - (no title--Kariba Dam) (no author indicated), undated (Box 447, Folder 7)
    - (no title--Dunkirk) (no author indicated), undated (Box 447, Folder 8)
    - (no title--Beyond the Fringe) (no author indicated), undated (Box 447, Folder 9)
    - (no title--Juvenile Delinquency) (no author indicated), undated (Box 447, Folder 10)
    - (no title--U.N. Declaration of the Rights of the Child) (no author indicated), undated (Box 447, Folder 11)
    - (no title--Warsaw) (no author indicated), undated (Box 447, Folder 12)
    - (no title--Concentration camps) (no author indicated), undated (Box 447, Folder 13)
  - INTERVIEW SPECIALS
    - Pearl Buck Mrs. Richard J. Walsh, Jr. Producer: James Nelson Director: John Bloch, 1959 May 3 (Box 447, Folder 14)
    - Pablo Casals Madeline Foley Producer: Robert D. Graff Director: Jacques Baratier, 1955 Jul 31 (Box 447, Folder 15)
    - Chiang Kai Shek, undated (Box 447, Folder 16)
    - Allan Nevins Henry Steele Commager, 1963 Jul 31 (Box 447, Folder 17)
    - Harry Emerson Fosdick (2 copies) Eugene Exman, 1959 May 10 (Box 447, Folder 18)
    - Louis Finklestein Producer: Doris Ann Director: Martin Hoade, undated (Box 447, Folder 19)
    - Herbert Hoover, undated (Box 447, Folder 20)
    - Archibald MacLeish Mark Van Doren, 1962 Aug 2 (Box 447, Folder 21)
    - Field Marshall Montgomery, 1959 Apr 28 (Box 447, Folder 22)
    - Jonas Salk, undated (Box 447, Folder 23)
    - Alfred P. Sloan, 1954 Mar (Box 447, Folder 24)
    - Arnold Toynbee, undated (Box 447, Folder 25)
    - Frank Lloyd Wright, undated (Box 447, Folder 26)
  - Drama, partial scripts
    Box 448 contains parts of dramas, usually one or two acts, that have become separated from the rest of the original script, and whose series is unidentifiable.
    - Autumn Nocturne Act II (Box 448, Folder 1)
    - The Baby Acts II and III (Box 448, Folder 2)
    - The Broken Fist Acts II and III (Box 448, Folder 3)
    - Catch My Boy on Sunday Act III (Box 448, Folder 4)
    - Man and Superman Acts I and II G.B. Shaw Joseph Schrank (Milberg Productions, Inc.) (Box 448, Folder 5)
    - Moment of Truth Act II (Box 448, Folder 6)
    - Recoil Act II (N.B. The remainder of this script exists somewhere in the main catalog.) (Box 448, Folder 7)
    - A Room in Paris Acts II and III (Box 448, Folder 8)
    - The Sorcerer's Apprentice Act I (Box 448, Folder 9)
    - Thunder of Silence Acts II and III (Box 448, Folder 10)
    - no title Acts II and III (Box 448, Folder 11)
    - no title Acts II and III #63 from the rest of the original script and which cannot be identified in any way. (Box 448, Folder 12)
  - Drama, scripts lacking title page
    Box 449 contains dramas which appear complete or almost complete, but have no title pages or other series identification.
    - Jamie and the Wallflower (Box 449, Folder 1)
    - The Killer Instinct (Box 449, Folder 2)
    - The Way Things Happen (Box 449, Folder 3)
    - no title (Box 449, Folder 4)
    - no title (Box 449, Folder 5)
    - no title (Box 449, Folder 6)
    - no title (Box 449, Folder 7)
    - no title (Box 449, Folder 8)
- Press Releases
  - Box 450 contains press releases for shows in the collection. (Box 450)
    (N.B. Many press releases remain attached to the individual shows.)
- Oversize (legal size)
  - Box 451 contains oversize scripts. These are noted in the catalgog where they occur. (Box 451)
- TV Key files and printed material
  - The Television Annual (draft), 1978-79 (Box 452, Folder 1-7)
    Reference listings of television shows and movies, including criticism.
  - Hamlet, a Television Script, 1959 Feb 24 (Box 452, Folder 8)
  - Synopses of Movies, 1952-56 (Box 453, Folder 1)
    One page synopses of movies released between 1952-56, including cast and production credits.
  - NBC Matinee Theatre Story Reports, 1955-56 (Box 453, Folder 2)
  - TV Key Files, 1954-58, undated (Box 453, Folder 3)
    Publicity files, draft notes and synopses, and blank letterhead
  - Trade Publications, 1955-63 (Box 453, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960-62, undated (Box 453, Folder 5)